A Guide to the Virginia Craftsmen Ledgers, 1938-1955
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Special Collections, James Madison University
Virginia Craftsmen Ledgers, 1938-1955
Special Collections, James Madison University
SC 5061
9 Hollinger boxes (3.75 linear feet)
The collection consists of the business ledgers of the Virginia Craftsmen of Harrisonburg, Virginia from 1938-1955.
Virginia Craftsmen
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
The ledgers were donated in march of 2012 by Susan Versen, Head of Reference at Massanutten Regional Library.
Provenance
The former director of the Massanutten Regional Library pulled the records from the Craft House in downtown Harrisonburg before it was demolished.
Biographical Information
Founded in 1927, Virginia Craftsmen supplies handmade, reproduction 18th century furniture. They have provided furniture to Monticello, Colonial Williamsburg, the capitol rotunda, and other historical sites. They originally operated out of Harrisonburg, Virginia. The Virginia Craftsmen still make furniture, but they are now located in Hinton, Virginia. Carrier Library is in possession of multiple chairs made by the Virginia Craftsmen.
Scope and Content
The Virginia Craftsmen Ledgers, 1938-1955, consist of 3.75 linear feet of material. The collection consists of the business ledgers of the Virginia Craftsmen of Harrisonburg Virginia. Each page is a record of how many and what type of item was bought, the buyer of the item, and where the item would be shipped. The collection is arranged in 9 series, with each ledger being its own series.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in chronological order.
The collection is arranged in IX series:
I: 1938-1940
II: 1940-1942
III: 1947-1948
IV: 1948-1949
V: 1950-1951
VI: 1951-1952
VII: 1952-1953
VIII: 1953-1954
IX: 1955
Contents List
- 1938-1940
  - December 1938 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - January 1939 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - February 1939 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - March 1939 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - April 1939 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - May 1939 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - June 1939 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - July 1938 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - August 1939 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - September 1939 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - October 1939 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - November 1939 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - December 1939 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - December 1939 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 1:15)
- 1940-1942
  - February 1940 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - March 1940 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - April 1940 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - May 1940 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - June 1940 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - July 1940 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - August 1940 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - September 1940 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - October 1940 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - November 1940 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - December 1940 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - January 1941 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - February 1941 (Box-folder 2:13)
  - March 1941 (Box-folder 2:14)
  - April 1941 (Box-folder 2:15)
  - May 1941 (Box-folder 2:16)
  - June 1941 (Box-folder 2:17)
  - July 1941 (Box-folder 2:18)
  - August 1941 (Box-folder 2:19)
  - September 1941 (Box-folder 2:20)
  - October 1941 (Box-folder 2:21)
  - November 1941 (Box-folder 2:22)
  - December 1941 (Box-folder 2:23)
  - January 1942 (Box-folder 2:24)
- 1947-1948
  - April 1947 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - May 1947 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - June 1947 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - July 1947 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - August 1947 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - September 1947 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - October 1947 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - November 1947 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - December 1947 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - January 1948 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - February 1948 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - March 1948 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - April 1948 (Box-folder 3:13)
  - May 1948 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - June 1948 (Box-folder 3:15)
- 1948-1949
  - July 1948 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - August 1948 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - September 1948 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - October 1948 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - November 1948 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - December 1948 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - January 1949 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - February 1949 (Box-folder 4:8)
  - March 1949 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - April 1949 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - May 1949 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - June 1949 (Box-folder 4:12)
- 1950-1951
  - October 1950 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - November 1950 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - December 1950 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - January 1951 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - February 1951 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - March 1951 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - April 1951 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - May 1951 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - June 1951 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - July 1951 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - August 1951 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - September 1951 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - October 1951 (Box-folder 5:13)
- 1951-1952
  - November 1951 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - December 1951 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - January 1952 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - February 1952 (Box-folder 6:4)
  - March 1952 (Box-folder 6:5)
  - April 1952 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - May 1952 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - June 1952 (Box-folder 6:8)
  - July 1952 (Box-folder 6:9)
  - August 1952 (Box-folder 6:10)
  - September 1952 (Box-folder 6:11)
  - October 1952 (Box-folder 6:12)
- 1953-1954
  - November 1952 (Box-folder 7:1)
  - December 1952 (Box-folder 7:2)
  - January 1953 (Box-folder 7:3)
  - February 1953 (Box-folder 7:4)
  - March 1953 (Box-folder 7:5)
  - April 1953 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - May 1953 (Box-folder 7:7)
  - June 1953 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - July 1953 (Box-folder 7:9)
  - August 1953 (Box-folder 7:10)
  - September 1953 (Box-folder 7:11)
  - October 1953 (Box-folder 7:12)
- 1953-1954
  - November 1953 (Box-folder 8:1)
  - December 1953 (Box-folder 8:2)
  - January 1954 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - February 1954 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - March 1954 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - April 1954 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - May 1954 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - June 1954 (Box-folder 8:8)
  - July 1954 (Box-folder 8:9)
  - August 1953 (Box-folder 8:10)
  - September 1954 (Box-folder 8:11)
  - October 1954 (Box-folder 8:12)
  - November 1954 (Box-folder 8:13)
  - December 1954 (Box-folder 8:14)
- 1955
  - January 1955 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - February 1955 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - March 1955 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - April 1955 (Box-folder 9:4)
  - May 1955 (Box-folder 9:5)
  - June 1955 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - July 1955 (Box-folder 9:7)
  - August 1955 (Box-folder 9:8)
  - September 1955 (Box-folder 9:9)
  - October 1955 (Box-folder 9:10)
  - November 1955 (Box-folder 9:11)
  - December 1955 (Box-folder 9:12)